Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/pacecarter (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Mergers & Acquisitions (M&A)

Due Diligence

Financial Modeling

Certifications

Microsoft Excel (Microsoft 365 Apps and Office 2019)

Pace J. Carter

USU Finance and Economics Major | Intern Analyst for Partners Real Estate Fund | Trilingual

Logan, Utah, United States

Summary

Experienced investment analyst with a passion for Private Markets/ Venture Capital. Motivated and analytically minded student studying finance at the Jon M. Huntsman School of Business. Raised in 3 different countries, I became fluent in English, Portuguese, and French. Skilled in Microsoft Excel, Bloomberg, SQL, Stata, Python, PitchBook, and Account Management.

Experience

Utah State University - Jon M. Huntsman School of Business Portfolio Manager | Team Lead January 2023 - Present (4 months)

Logan, Utah, United States

- Prepare investment strategies and plans
- Perform daily market research through Bloomberg and analyze specific stocks to make equity investment recommendations in team of 7
- Meet weekly with team to discuss financial markets, risks, portfolio returns, and segment strategies

Partners Real Estate Fund Investment Analyst Intern December 2022 - Present (5 months)

Logan, Utah, United States

- Develop financial models and underwrite real estate investments
- Allocate capital to real estate projects
- Perform market research related to specific properties, projects, and potential investments

Verizon
Sales Representative
February 2021 - Present (2 years 3 months)
Logan, Utah, United States

- Lead Utah, Montana, Nevada, and Idaho territory with a 94% insurance attach rate (53% company target) and 100% customer satisfaction scores
- First of 300 territory sales reps in new priority metrics such as Verizon Visa and Verizon Home Protect as well as phone growth performance
- Sell 20+ different products and services to hundreds of walk-in customers per month. Process 1000+ credit applications

IndustryPro Investment Banking Analyst Intern December 2022 - April 2023 (5 months)

- Analyze firms with valuations of \$10-\$250 million for M&A opportunities
- Work alongside executives and current analysts to gain experience in financial modeling, deal flow, and negotiations between PE firms and business owners

Tingue

Outside Sales Representative October 2019 - February 2021 (1 year 5 months)

- Established 13 new accounts by cold calling and referrals and maintained relationships with 40+ accounts in Kentucky, Tennessee, Indiana, and Ohio
- Closed orders worth \$300k+ from several different customers in commercial laundry industry
- Exceeded sales quotas by 20% quarterly and attended 6 nationwide sales meetings sharpening sales skills

Murdock Hyundai of Logan Sales Professional July 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 6 months) North Logan, Utah, United States

- Consistent top salesperson of 12 averaging 18 cars per month valued at \$280k in sales
- Personally met and qualified 500+ customers presenting options based on finances and availability
- Broke all-time sales records and earned awards for "Best Month Ever" and "Most Cars Sold in One Month" Aug and Sep 2019
- Qualified warm internet leads and generated new traffic with 72% conversion rate and 96% customer satisfaction rate

Dirty P's (snow cone business) Founder

September 2017 - July 2018 (11 months)

Logan, Utah, United States

- Invested \$2,700 in construction, licensing, and inventory. Sold business for 475% ROI
- Hired and trained 5 staff members
- Researched and created business plan describing company vision and strategy
- Maintained business bank accounts, payment processing, accounts payable/ accounts receivable, and taxes
- Designed and implemented search engine optimization and social media marketing strategies

Education

Utah State University - Jon M. Huntsman School of Business Bachelor of Arts - BA, Finance and Economics · (August 2018 - May 2023)